

Full Stack Developer renegrooth@gmail.com 0211802090

Auckland, New Zealand

# Rene Groothuis

### **Profile**

After working as an Electrician for 7 years on an expansive range of projects, I wanted to develop my problem-solving analytical and creative skills further. In order to improve on these skills I learnt as an electrician I have undertaken additional training and to refocus my skills towards Software Development.

I enjoyed the programming / problem solving side of being an Electrician so I commited to Software Devlopment by attending Dev Academy Aotearoa. In my new career I hope to continue solving complex problems with creativity and collaboration.

# **Experience**

# Apprentice Software Developer at Dev Academy Aotearoa, Auckland

01/2023-05/2023

- This was a life-changing 17-week full-immersion software development bootcamp that closely represents working in a modern development team. The course taught me a modern development stack.
- Over these weeks I learnt JavaScript, Typescript, React, Redux, SQlite3 with knex, Node.js, Express.js.
- We worked in pairs, groups and solo to work on improving our technical skills and human skills to complete projects and assingments.
- During our final week we worked in a team
   of five to develop a web based app together
   https://github.com/harakeke-2023/Squishy-Squish. This was a 2D
   paltformer game we made using p5.js and react. In order to complete
   this project we learnt a new technology (p5) and applied it to what we
   had learned during the course.

#### Electrician at Prolectrics, Auckland

11/2018-12/2022

- Worked well independently and in a team to solve problems, working on multipule different projects that required a wide range of knowledge and organisation.
- Served as a friendly, hardworking, and punctual employee.
- Organised and prioritized work to complete assignments in a timely, efficient manner.
- Remained committed to adding to my knowledge and skills base, keeping up with the latest trends in the electrical space.
- Designed, planed, and executed new installs and regular maintenance for a wide range of customers.
- Work along side factorys to maintain, diagnose and repair machines, including upgrading safety systems, installing new circuits and testing and repairing emergency systems.

#### Electrician apprentice at ETCO, Auckland

08/2016-11/2018

Did my apprenticeship training through ETCO where we worked with different companies to learn a wide range of electrical skills. Including residential, commercial and industrial.

#### Links

<u>GitHub</u> <u>LinkedIn</u> Personal Website

### **Skills**

Typescript
React
Redux
Node.js
SQlite3
Ability to Work in a Team
Computer Skills
Electrical Wiring
Troubleshooting
Safe Work Practices

#### **Hobbies**

In my spare time I enjoy running, going to the gym, football and skiing in winter

## References

References available upon request

# **Education**

Level 6 Applied Technology of Software

Development, Dev Academy Aotearoa, Auckland

01/2023-05/2023

An intensive 17-week web development training program that replicates real industry work with a focus on technical and non-technical skills.

#### Level 4 Electrical Engineering, ETCO, Auckland

01/2017-11/2019

New Zealand Certificate in Electrical Engineering Theory and Practice (Trade) (Level 4).